Finding Aid for Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association records, 1987-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association records 1987-2008
Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association.
1.5 linear feet
2010092 Aa 2
Records of the Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association (SEMJA) covering the history and activities of the organization.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Lars Bjorn (donor no. 10345 ) in 2010.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association was established in 1987 in Ann Arbor, Mich. as a volunteer organization. SEMJA provides jazz education to students at all levels through special programs in schools and in the community, supports live performances of jazz in Southeastern Michigan, provides information about jazz through publication of monthly newsletter "Update," provides a community for area jazz musicians and fans, and promotes the understanding of jazz as an art form.
The Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association records collection includes organization's administrative and financial files and visual material related to various SEMJA programs and activities.
Subjects:
Big bands--Michigan, Southeastern.; Jazz--Michigan, Southeastern.; Jazz--Performances--Michigan, Southeastern.; Jazz festivals--Michigan, Southeastern.; Jazz musicians--Michigan, Southeastern.; Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association.; Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bands--Michigan.; Jazz festivals--Michigan, Southeastern.; Jazz musicians--Michigan, Southeastern.; Musicians--Michigan, Southeastern.; Southeastern Michigan Jazz Association.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Administrative files
  The Administrative files series includes SEMJA by-laws and statement of purpose, agendas, meeting minutes, and notices of annual members meetings and of monthly Board meetings, lists of members, reports to the Board and to the annual meeting, summaries of annual activities, and correspondence. Also included Treasurer's financial reports, fundraisers reports, assessment of costs, and SEMJA merchandise description and sales reports.
  - Board of Members
    - Mission, by-laws and SEMJA history (Box 1)
    - Annual meetings announcements, agendas and minutes, 1988-2006 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - SEMJA membership, 1998-2003 (Box 1)
    - Board of Members meetings agendas, minutes and reports, 1987-2006, 19 folders (Box 1)
    - Board of Members, 1994-2006 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1997-2006, undated (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Financial records
    - Reports, 1988-2007, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Program costs and fundraisers, 1995-2002 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - SEMJA merchandise, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
- Activities and programs
  The Activities and programs series contains descriptions, announcements, correspondence, and other material related to specific programs, program reports, Project Director's file, correspondence, reports of the Program Chair and Program Committee reviews, program proposals from within SEMJA and from outside organizations. Also included press releases and examples of media coverage. Miscellaneous material consists of lists of names of area musicians and communications professionals, business cards, and miscellaneous handwritten notes.
  - Programs
    - Black History, 1990, 1995, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - Christmas Party, 1987-1993 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Jazz Educators programs, 1988-1992 (Box 1)
    - Jazz Goes to Ashley Street, 1993 undated (Box 1)
    - Jazz Goes to Market, 1991, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Meet the Artist, 1987-1990 (Box 1)
    - Youth Jazz Workshop, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Programs, various, 1987-1990, 1992-2003, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Program reports
    - 1990-1992, 1995-1997, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Project Director
    - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 1)
  - Program proposals
    - SEMJA program proposals, 1990-2005 (scattered), undated (Box 1)
    - Program proposals, outside, 1988-1992 (scattered), undated (Box 1)
  - Press releases and media coverage
    - 1988-2004 scattered (Box 1)
- Visual materials
  The Visual materials series contains flyers, concert programs and handouts, undated photographs from performances and the 1996 Phynxhorne Jazz Calendar printed by Other Wind Press, Inc. in Ann Arbor, Mich., featuring photographs taken during performances in Ann Arbor, Detroit, and Flint.
  - Flyers and handouts, 1993-2003, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - 1996: Phynxhorne Jazz Calendar (Box 1)
- Printed materials
  The Printed materials series consists of the 1987-2008 run of the SEMJA newsletters.
  - Newsletter, 1987-1990 (Box 2)
  - Jazz update, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Update, 1991-2008, 18 folders (Box 2)